Finding Aid for the J. Paul Getty Trust Inventory of Getty Publications, 1954-2013 and undated IA10020
Institutional Records and Archives
- Getty Center for the History of Art and the Humanities (GCHAH) and Getty Research Institute (GRI), 1985-1991; 1994-2013,; undated; Series III.
  - Perchuk, Andrew, and Rani Singh, eds. Harry Smith: The Avant-Garde in the American Vernacular. Los Angeles: 2010. (Box 2012.IA.01-30)
  - Pevsner, Nikolaus. Visual Planning and the Picturesque. Los Angeles: 2010. (Box 2012.IA.01-10)
  - Riegl, Alois. The Origins of Baroque Art in Rome. Translated by Andrew Hopkins and Arnold Witte. Los Angeles: 2010. (Box 2011.IA.01-04)
  - Cody, Jeffrey W., and Francis Terpak, eds. Brush & Shutter: Early Photography in China. Los Angeles: 2011. (Box 2013.IA.01-4)
  - Feigenbaum, Gail, and Sybille Ebert-Schifferer, eds.Sacred Possessions: Collecting Italian Religious Art, 1500-1900. Los Angeles: 2011. (Box 2011.IA.01-04)
  - Gaehtgens, Thomas W., and Louis Marchesano. Display Art History: The Düsseldorf Gallery and Its Catalogue. Los Angeles: 2011. (Box 2013.IA.01-1)
  - Gaehtgens, Thomas W., ed. Getty Research Journal; Number 3. Los Angeles: 2011. (Box 2013.IA.01-2)
  - The Getty Research Institute: Special Collections. [Los Angeles]: 2011. (Box 2012.IA.01-12)
  - Gruen, Erich S. Cultural Identity in the Ancient Mediterranean. Los Angeles: 2011. (Box 2013.IA.01-2)
  - Preimesberger, Rudolf. Paragons and Paragone: Van Eyck, Raphael, Michelangelo, Caravaggio, Bernini. Los Angeles: 2011. (Box 2013.IA.01-2)
  - Reed, Marcia, and Paola Dematte, eds. China on Paper: European and Chinese Works from the Late Sixteenth to Early Nineteenth Century. Los Angeles: 2011. (Box 2011.IA.01-04)
  - Ades, Dawn, Rita Eder, and Graciela Speranza, eds. Surrealism in Latin America: Vivísimo Muerto. Los Angeles: 2012. (Box 2012.IA.01-30)
  - Feigenbaum, Gail, and Inge Reist, eds. Provenance: An Alternate History of Art. Los Angeles: 2012. (Box 2013.IA.01-2)
  - Leddy, Annette, and Donna Conwell. Farewell to Surrealism: The DYN Circle in Mexico. Los Angeles: 2012. (Box 2012.IA.01-29)
  - Paleotti, Gabriele. Discourse on Sacred and Profane Images. Translation by William McCuaig. Los Angeles: 2012. (Box 2012.IA.01-30)
  - Quatremère de Quincy, Antoine. Letters to Miranda and Canova on the Abduction of Antiquities from Rome and Athens. Translated by Chris Miller and David Gilks. Los Angeles: 2012. (Box 2013.IA.01-2)
  - Behdad, Ali, and Luke Gartlan, eds. Photography's Orientalism: New Essays on Colonial Representation. Los Angeles: 2013. (Box 2013.IA.01-3)
  - De Wit, Wim, and Christopher James Alexander, eds. Overdrive: L.A. Constructs the Future 1940-1990. Los Angeles: 2013. (Box 2013.IA.01-4)
  - Matisse, Henri, and Pierre Courthion. Chatting with Henri Matisse: The Lost 1941 Interview. Translated by Chris Miller. Los Angeles: 2013. (Box 2013.IA.01-3)
  - Pénichon, Sylvie. Twentieth-Century Color Photographs: Identification and Care. Los Angeles: 2013. (Box 2013.IA.01-3)
  - Stierli, Martin. Las Vegas in the Rearview Mirror: The City in Theory, Photography, and Film. Translated by Elizabeth Tucker. Los Angeles: 2013. (Box 2013.IA.01-1)
  - Getty Community Outreach Summary. (Box 2010.IA.01-15)
- Project for Art on Film, 1990-1994; Series IV.
  The Program for Art on Film was founded in 1984 as a joint venture between the J. Paul Getty Trust and the Metropolitan Museum of Art as a pilot project that would eventually become independent from its founding institutions. The Program's purpose was to define issues, develop programs, and disseminate information that would support the effective production and use of moving-image media that contribute to a better understanding and appreciation of the visual arts.
  From 1984, the Getty Trust, through a joint venture with the Metropolitan Museum, subsidized the development of the Art on Screen Database and the Program's other projects. The Trust's support made it possible for the Program to offer a range of services to the field for free or at minimal cost during this productive development period under the joint venture, which concluded in June of 1994. From July 1994 through June 1996, the Program was based at Columbia University.
  The Program was then established as an independent, non-profit 501(c)(3) corporation. In 1996 the Program affiliated with the Pratt Institute and moved its offices to the School of Information and Library Science (SILS) building, on the Institute's main campus in Brooklyn, New York. Some of the resulting programs enabled by this new joint venture were the Art on Screen and Architecture on Screen festivals.
  Among the reference works produced by the Program were: the Art on Film Database, begun in 1984; Films and Videos on Photography, in collaboration with the Direction des Musées de France, Ministry of Culture and Communication, Paris, in both English and French editions; Art on Screen: A Directory of Films and Videos about the Visual Arts (G.K. Hall & Co., 1992); Art on Screen, a newsletter of the visual arts, and Close-Ups, the Art on Film Database Service supplement of reviews and recommended film titles; Architecture on Screen (G.K. Hall & Co., 1994); Art Museums and Media (1994), a report of survey results; and The Art on Screen Handbook: Practical Guidelines for Using and Producing Films, Videos and Interactive Programs about Art (1994).
  Material comprises publications by or about the Project for Art on Film.
  - Films on Art Biography. 1990. (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
  - Covert, Nadine, ed.Art on Screen: A Directory of Films and Videos About the Visual Arts. 1991. (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
  - Films on Art Biography. 1992. (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
  - Architecture on Screen: A Directory of Films and Videos. 1993. (Box 1987.IA.04-13)
  - Covert, Nadine, Vivian Wick, Susan Logan, Teresa Russo, and Carole Lazio, comps. Films on Art Biography. 1994. (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
- Getty Art History Information Program and Getty Information Institute, 1984-1988; 1990-1999,; undated; Series V.
  The Getty Information Institute (GII) was the name given to the Getty Art History Information Program (AHIP) when AHIP was retitled in 1996. During the 1980s, as personal computers became tools for scholarly research, the Art History Information Program pioneered research on the informational needs of art historians and was the driving force behind several collaborative projects concerning art-related texts and images that provided unprecedented automation of, digitization of, and access to these types of materials. During the 1990s, as the Internet and the World Wide Web became accessible to an increasing number of people, AHIP / GII played dynamic roles in several collaborative initiatives to standardize data management practices and to establish electronic networks that would bring together the resources of diverse cultural heritage institutions.
  AHIP was envisioned as early as 1981 with the following goal: to create "a set of linked data banks, some created by the Getty, the rest of diverse international origin, containing the varied types of information used by art historians –- bibliographical indexes, biographical indexes, catalogues of works, images of works, and a host of other related data and texts to facilitate the scholar's work, all accessible through simple, unified, and inexpensive means by individual scholars around the world working at personal computers without intermediaries" (AHIP memo, February 1986). In 1984 Nancy Englander (then Director of Program Planning and Analysis) presented key elements of the emerging Art History Information Program to the Getty Board of Trustees, including a number of databases. AHIP became a program under the J. Paul Getty Trust and a pioneer in databases for the arts and humanities. Although AHIP and its departments seem to have been officially named circa 1986, many of the activities and projects under its supervision were well underway before that time.
  Some of the initial projects undertaken by AHIP were:
  The Census of Antique Art and Architecture Known to the Renaissance, which began in 1946 as a file of text and images in the Warburg Institute of London, was expanded by the Bibliotheca Hertziana (Rome) in 1982, and whose automation was sponsored by the Getty in 1984
  The Art and Architecture Thesaurus® (AAT), a database of standardized vocabulary that was designed in the 1970s to merge redundant and contradictory subject headings from various controlled vocabularies related to objects and monuments and was acquired by the Getty in 1983
  The Scuola Normale / Getty (SN/G), a database of "automated projects in the history of art worldwide" that was a collaboration with the Scuola Normale Superiore in Pisa, Italy; and
  In the 1980s AHIP contributed significantly to the understanding of scholarly computing needs, the production and availability of electronic resources, and the standardization of information in the arts and humanities. During this time the Getty conducted studies on the image quality needs of researchers and the use of electronic images and text in the academic environment.
  In the 1990s AHIP became increasingly involved in national discussions regarding technology and the "information superhighway" or "data highway," becoming less centered on data collection and increasingly concerned with how data was structured, automated, maintained, and accessed. Its projects and collaborative efforts became focused on the long term viability of automated information and the standards needed to ensure that viability. AHIP's goal was to take a leadership role in the development of information standards and policies and help the art historical and cultural heritage communities prepare for and utilize new technologies. In late 1993 AHIP shifted its concentration from database production and products to the issues and policies emerging around information networks, focusing on the standards governing data management practices.
  AHIP / GII was a program developed and overseen by the J. Paul Getty Trust, a cultural and philanthropic organization serving both general audiences and specialized professionals. AHIP's name was changed to the Getty Information Institute (GII) in 1996 as part of a new identity program instituted by the Trust just prior to occupancy of their new unified facility, the Getty Center (Brentwood, California). The GII was dissolved in 1999, and many of its functions were absorbed by the Getty Research Institute (GRI).
  Material comprises Getty publications produced by or about the activities of the Getty Information Institute and its predecessor, the Getty Art History Information Program. Series of publications, such as BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, were continued by the GRI from 1999 forward.
  - Corti, Laura, ed.Census: Computerization in the History of Art. Los Angeles: 1984. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 14)
  - Corti, Laura, and Marilyn Schmitt, eds. Automatic Processing of Art History Data & Documents, Volume 1: Pisa, Scuola normale superiore, September 24-27, 1984: proceedings. Florence, Italy: 1984. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 14)
  - Corti, Laura, and Marilyn Schmitt, eds. Automatic Processing of Art History Data & Documents, Volume 2: Pisa, Scuola normale superiore, September 24-27, 1984: proceedings. Florence, Italy: 1984. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 14)
  - Corcoran Stam, Deirdre. A Handbook on Authority Work in Automated Art Information Systems, Draft, April 1, 1987. 1987. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
  - Bakewell, Elizabeth, William O. Beeman, and Carol McMichael Reese. Object, Image, Inquiry: The Art Historian at Work. Santa Monica: 1988. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 14)
    General note
    (2 Copies)
  - Fredericksen, Burton B., ed. The Index of Paintings Sold in the British Isles during the Nineteenth Century 1801-1805, Volume I. Santa Barbara, CA: 1988. (Box 2012.IA.01-25)
  - SN/G: Report on Data Processing Projects in Art – Indexes (1988). (Box 1987.IA.04 - 14)
  - SN/G: Report on Data Processing Projects in Art – Projects (1988). (Box 1987.IA.04 - 14)
  - RILA (Repertoire International de la Litterature de L'Art/International Repertory of the Literature of Art), Volume 15. New York: 1989. (Box 2012.IA.01-27)
  - Art & Architecture, Volume 1, Part I: Introduction, Part II: Hierarchal Displays. New York: 1990. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Art & Architecture, Volume 2, Part III: Alphabetic Display. New York: 1990. (Box 2010.IA.01-14)
  - Art & Architecture, Volume 3, Part III: Alphabetical Display (Continued). New York: 1990. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
  - Fredericksen, Burton B., ed. The Index of Paintings Sold in the British Isles during the Nineteenth Century 1806-1810, Volume 2, Part 1. Santa Barbara, CA: 1990. (Box 2012.IA.01-25)
  - Fredericksen, Burton B., ed. The Index of Paintings Sold in the British Isles during the Nineteenth Century 1806-1810, Volume 2, Part 2. Santa Barbara, CA: 1990. (Box 2012.IA.01-25)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 1, Cumulative Index. Santa Monica: 1991. (Box 2010.IA.01-06)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 1/1. Santa Monica: 1991. (Box 2010.IA.01-06)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 1/2. Santa Monica: 1991. (Box 2010.IA.01-06)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 1/3. Santa Monica: 1991. (Box 2010.IA.01-06)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 1/4. Santa Monica: 1991. (Box 2010.IA.01-06)
  - Siegfried, Susan L. and Julie Bernstein.Synoname: The Getty's Approach to Pattern Matching for Personal Names. Santa Monica: 1991. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
    According to WorldCat, was an article in "Computers and the Humanities," v25 n4 (Aug., 1991): 211-226
  - Art & Architecture Thesaurus, Supplement 1. Oxford University Press, New York: 1992. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 2, Cumulative Index. Santa Monica: 1992. (Box 2010.IA.01-07)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 2/1. Santa Monica: 1992. (Box 2010.IA.01-07)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 2/2. Santa Monica: 1992. (Box 2010.IA.01-07)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 2/3. Santa Monica: 1992. (Box 2010.IA.01-07)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 2/4. Santa Monica: 1992. (Box 2010.IA.01-07)
  - Bibliography of the History of Art. Centre national de la recherche scientifique, Institut de l'information scientifique et technique, Vandoeuvre-les-Nancy, France and Santa Monica: 1992. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
  - Thuillier, Jacques and Marie-Francoise Clergeau. International Database of Artists' Biographical Data, Manual. 1992. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 3/1. Santa Monica: 1993. (Box 2010.IA.01-07)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 3/2. Santa Monica: 1993. (Box 2010.IA.01-07)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 3/3. Santa Monica: 1993. (Box 2010.IA.01-07)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 3/4. Santa Monica: 1993. (Box 2010.IA.01-07)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 3, Cumulative Index. Santa Monica: 1993. (Box 2010.IA.01-08)
  - The Census of Antique Art and Architecture Known to the Renaissance. Santa Monica: 1993. (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
  - Technology, Scholarship, and the Humanities: The Implications of Electronic Information, September 30-October 2, 1992, Summary of Proceedings. Los Angeles: 1993. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
  - Technology, Scholarship, and the Humanities: The Implications of Electronic Information, September 30-October 2, 1992, Summary of Proceedings. Los Angeles: 1993. (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
  - Authority Reference Tool Version 2.0 for the Art and Architecture Thesaurus. New York: 1994. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 15)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 4/1. Santa Monica: 1994. (Box 2010.IA.01-08)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 4/2. Santa Monica: 1994. (Box 2010.IA.01-08)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 4/3. Santa Monica: 1994. (Box 2010.IA.01-08)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 4/4. Santa Monica: 1994. (Box 2010.IA.01-08)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 4, Cumulative Index. Santa Monica: 1994. (Box 2010.IA.01-08)
  - Education and Cultural Heritage: Solid Partners for the NII: Current and Emerging Projects and Approaches, January 14, 1995, Project Descriptions. Santa Monica: 1994. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
  - A Guide to the Description of Architectural Drawings. New York: 1994., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 15)
  - Humanities and Arts on the Information Highways: A Profile: September 1994. Santa Monica: 1994. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
  - Introduction to the Art & Architecture Thesaurus. New York: 1994. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 15)
  - Petersen, Toni, and Patricia J. Barnett, eds. Guide to Indexing and Cataloging with the Art & Architecture Thesaurus. Oxford and New York: 1994. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
  - Union List of Artist Names: User's Guide to the Authority Reference Tool. 1994., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 15)
  - Users Guide to the Documents for the History of Collecting on CD-ROM. 1994., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 15)
  - Beser, Howard & Jennifer Trant. Introduction to Imaging. Santa Monica: 1995., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 15)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 5/1. Santa Monica: 1995. (Box 2010.IA.01-08)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 5/1. Santa Monica: 1995. (Box 2010.IA.01-08)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 5/3. Santa Monica: 1995. (Box 2010.IA.01-09)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 5/4. Santa Monica: 1995. (Box 2010.IA.01-09)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 5, Cumulative Index. Santa Monica, Ca: 1995. (Box 2010.IA.01-09)
  - Thornes, Robin. Protecting Cultural Objects. Santa Monica: 1995. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 15)
  - Thornes, Robin. Protecting Cultural Objects Through International Documentation Standards: A Preliminary Survey. Los Angeles: 1995. (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
  - Art Information Task Force. Categories for the Description of Works of Art. Santa Monica: 1996. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
  - Art Information Task Force. Categories for the Description of Works of Art. Santa Monica: 1996. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 6/1. Santa Monica: 1996. (Box 2010.IA.01-09)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 6/2. Santa Monica: 1996. (Box 2010.IA.01-09)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 6/3. Santa Monica: 1996. (Box 2010.IA.01-09)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 6/4. Santa Monica: 1996. (Box 2010.IA.01-09)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 6, Cumulative Index, English. Santa Monica: 1996. (Box 2010.IA.01-09)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 6, Index Cumulatif, Francais. Santa Monica: 1996. (Box 2010.IA.01-10)
  - Getty Provenance Index: User's Guide to the Cumulative Edition on CD-ROM. 1996., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 15)
  - Research Agenda for Networked Cultural Heritage. Santa Monica: 1996., (2 copies) (Box 1987.IA.04 - 15)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 7/1. Santa Monica: 1997. (Box 2010.IA.01-10)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 7/2. Santa Monica: 1997. (Box 2010.IA.01-10)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 7/3. Santa Monica: 1997. (Box 2010.IA.01-10)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 7/4. Santa Monica: 1997. (Box 2010.IA.01-10)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 7, Cumulative Index. Santa Monica: 1997. (Box 2010.IA.01-10)
  - Thornes, Robin. Protecting Cultural Objects in the Global Information Society: The Making of Object ID. Los Angeles: 1997. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
  - Baca, Murtha, ed. Introducción a los Metadatos: Vías a la información digital. Los Angeles: 1998. (Box 2012.IA.01-27)
  - Baca, Murtha, ed. Introduction to Metadata: Pathways to Digital Information. Los Angeles: 1998. (Box 2012.IA.01-27)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 8/1. Santa Monica: 1998. (Box 2010.IA.01-10)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 8/2. Santa Monica: 1998. (Box 2010.IA.01-10)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 8/3. Santa Monica: 1998. (Box 2010.IA.01-11)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 8/4. Santa Monica: 1998. (Box 2010.IA.01-11)
  - BHA: Bibliography of the History of Art, Volume 8, Cumulative Index. Santa Monica: 1998. (Box 2010.IA.01-11)
  - Fox, Michael J., and Peter L Wilkerson. Introduction to Archival Organization and Description. Los Angeles: 1998 (Box 2012.IA.01-27)
  - Fredericksen, Burton B., ed. Corpus of Paintings Sold in the Netherlands during the Nineteenth Century, Volume 1: 1801-1810. Los Angeles: 1998. (Box 2012.IA.01-24)
  - Stephenson, Christie, and Patricia McClung, eds. Delivering Digital Images: Cultural Heritage resources for Education. Los Angeles: 1998. (Box 2012.IA.01-37)
    Series: The Museum Educational Site [MESL] Licensing Project, Volume 1.
  - Thornes, Robin, and John Bold, eds. La Documentation du Patrimoine Culturel: Sites Archaeologiques, Objets Culturels, Édifices Historiques. 1998 (Box 1987.IA.04 - 15)
  - Lansi, Elisa. Introduction to Vocabularies: Enhancing Access to Cultural Heritage Information. Los Angeles: 1998 (Box 2012.IA.01-27)
  - McClung, Patricia, and Christie Stephenson, eds.Images Online: Perspectives on the Museum Educational Site Licensing Project. Los Angeles: 1998 (Box 1987.IA.04 - 15)
  - Peronnet, Benjamin, and Burton B. Fredericksen, eds. Répertoire des Tableaux Vendus en France as XIXe Siècle, Volume 1 1801-1810, Tome 1 A-N. 1998. (Box 2012.IA.01-27)
  - Peronnet, Benjamin, and Burton B. Fredericksen, eds. Répertoire des Tableaux Vendus en France as XIXe Siècle, Volume 1 1801-1810, Tome 2 O-Z et Anonymes. 1998. (Box 2012.IA.01-27)
  - Users Guide to Thesaurus of Geographic Names: Relational Files Format. Los Angeles: 1998. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 15)
  - Users Guide to Thesaurus of Geographic Names: REC Format. Los Angeles: 1998. (Box 1987.IA.04 - 15)
  - La Formation D'Equivalents Linguistiques: Guide Modele sur L'Art & Architecture Thesaurus. Los Angeles: 199? (Box 2008.IA.01-01)
  - Guidelines for Forming Language Equivalents: A Model Based on the Art & Architecture Thesaurus. Sponsored by International Terminology Working Group. Los Angeles: 199?. (Box 2010.IA.01-13)
- Getty Center for Education in the Arts (GCEA), 1984-1999; undated; Series VI.
  The Getty Center for Education in the Arts, later known as the Getty Education Institute for the Arts (GEI), was one of the original programs established by the J. Paul Getty Trust, an international cultural and philanthropic organization serving both general audiences and specialized professionals. The Trust founded the Getty Center for Education in the Arts in 1982 with the mission of improving the quality and status of arts education in the nation's public schools. The education programs were guided by three premises: the visual arts should be an essential part of every child's education because knowledge of the arts is a principal means of understanding human experiences and transmitting cultural values; art education's content must be broadened to include instruction in art production, art history, art criticism, and aesthetics, an approach known as discipline-based art education (DBAE); and the most effective art education programs are based on partnerships among teachers, administrators, artists, museums, universities, and parents.